So we will see that we can define the embryo in terms of days,
那么我们将看到，我们可以用天数来定义胚胎，
we can also refer to Carnegie stages, but I will speak in terms of days.
我们也可以谈论卡内基分期，但我将用天数来告诉你们。
When there are synchronicities of phenomena,
当现象出现同步性时，
such as the closure of the neuropores with the integration of these somites and similar occurrences,
比如神经孔的闭合与这些体节的整合等等，
we would give you the timing, at the moment of cardiac awareness,
我们会告诉你们时间，比如心脏意识萌生之时，
such things, we would provide precise points.
诸如此类，我们会给出精确的时间点。
Otherwise, we will speak in terms of days or weeks.
否则，我们就会用天数或周数来表示。
And also, we will provide some notions of size.
此外，我们还会给出一些大小的概念。
What is truly important for you,
对你们来说真正重要的，
is the concept of growth.
是生长的概念。
It is to observe that it grows.
是要看到它在生长。
In fact, what needs to be understood,
事实上，需要理解的是，
is that it is a developmental movement.
这是一种发育运动。
In this approach, it is a movement
在这种方法中，它是一种运动，
that develops in this manner.
它是这样发展的。
But it is not a movement that occurs like this.
但它不是那样发生的运动。
This is the difference between what we call
这就是我们所说的，
motility and mobility.
动度（motility）和活动度（mobility）之间的区别。
One,
其中一个（指动度），
is an embryonic response,
是胚胎反应，
that is, it follows the movement
也就是说，它遵循着
of development,
发育的运动，
and the other is a movement
而另一个（指活动度）是
linked to respiration,
与呼吸相关的运动，
and which will generate movements,
并会产生运动，
and the other is a movement further attributed
还有一种运动则与
to motoricity.
运动能力有关。
You see, one must clearly differentiate.
你看，必须清楚地做出区分。
When I move like this, it is very different from
当我这样移动时，这与
this movement at the level of my liver.
我肝脏层面的这种运动非常不同。
So, if I want
所以，如果我想
to rework a tissue, I restore it
重新处理一个组织，我让它恢复
to its motility, and its functional strength, its functional strength is there, you
其自发性运动（motility），其功能性力量就在那里，你
see, that's where
看，就在那里
it will recover, and that's the work we do: returning to this tissue so that
它将恢复的地方，这就是我们所做的工作，回到这个组织中，以便
it can reorganize, regain its mobility, its motricity, you
它能够重新组织，在那里我能找回我的活动性（mobility）和运动性（motricity），你
understand, it's
明白吗，这是
always following the movement, but here you need the fulcrums, and after sensing the movement
总是跟随运动，但在这里需要支点，并且在掌握了运动之后
in your hand, I don't treat an organ, I treat an environment.
在手中，我不是治疗一个器官，我治疗的是一个环境
But sometimes, my action can be on motility, mobility,
但有时，我的作用可能涉及自发性运动（motility）、活动性（mobility）、
motricity.
运动性（motricity）。
And there, regarding mobility, what is it?
那么，在活动性（mobility）中，它是什么呢？
The master of mobility is the diaphragm.
活动性（mobility）的主宰是膈肌。
That's why we will learn how this diaphragm is built.
这就是为什么我们将学习膈肌是如何构建的。
One day, he taught me, he said, Marc, one day, you will feel the power in the tissue.
有一天，他教导我，他对我说，马克，有一天，你会在组织中感受到力量。
For me, the concept of power was very intellectual.
对我来说，这种力量是非常理性的概念。
At the same time, intellectually, I tell myself yes, I can understand that there is a kind of...
同时，从理性的角度，我对自己说，是的，我能理解有一种...
When I see an embryo developing, you can imagine the power of it.
当我看到一个胚胎发育时，你能想象那种力量吗？
It doesn't stop.
它不会停止。
There's an incredible power; it's astounding.
有一种力量，太不可思议了。
And he tells me sometimes, in the still points, in certain fulcrums, the power is there too.
他告诉我，有时，在某些风格中，在某些支点上，力量也存在。
It's incredible; there you can...
太不可思议了，在那里你可以...
Something happens, but you can't create that all the time.
会发生一些事情，但你无法一直创造它。
You must try to be present, to have a good connection, and then at some point...
你必须尝试活在当下，建立良好的连接，然后，在某个时刻...
the system adjusts
系统会自行调整
and then
然后
at one point he tells me
在某个时刻他告诉我
it's as if you were on a small boat in the sea
这就像你在一艘小船上，在大海中
you are just in the water
你就在水中
you don't see it, but beneath you
你看不见它，但在你下方
there is a whale
有一条鲸鱼
and you are just there, and you feel
而你就在那里感受
you suddenly feel
你突然间感受到
it's somewhat that sensation
有点像那种感觉
but observe
但是请看
first day
第一天
thank you
谢谢
the small, initial structure that we are,
我们这些微小的生命体，
and observe what will happen
再看看将会发生什么
at the end of the second month.
在第二个月末。
Observe, in two months,
请看，在两个月内，
what is already occurring.
已经发生了什么。
And observe already here,
再看这里，
at the beginning of the twentieth day,
在第二十天初期，
a form is already taking shape.
已经有了一个形态正在形成。
Here, the potential for life,
此刻，生命的潜能，
it is present. This is simply
它就在那里。这仅仅是
an ovum
一个卵子
which has received the genetic heritage
它接受了遗传基因
from the father,
来自父亲的，
thus, the spermatozoon.
也就是精子。
The two genetic heritages are in the process of converging.
这两种遗传基因正在结合。
This is approximately the first image of your life.
这大约是您生命中的第一个影像。
This is still referred to as the Zona Pellucida and nurse cells.
这仍然被称为透明带和滋养细胞。
Another layer of important cells.
又一层重要的细胞。